[
    {
        "question": "The shape of torque/slip curve of an induction motor is:",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Hyperbola",
            "b": "Ellipse",
            "c": "Straight line",
            "d": "Rectangular parabola "
        },
        "correctAnswer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Introducing the external resistance increases____.i. Speed ii. Output power iii. Starting torque",
        "answers": {
            "a": "iii",
            "b": "ii,iii",
            "c": "ii",
            "d": "i,iii,ii"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Introducing the external resistance decreases____. i. Speed ii. Output power iii. Starting torque",
        "answers": {
            "a": "iii",
            "b": "ii,iii",
            "c": "ii",
            "d": "i,iii,ii"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Slip v/s torque developed in an induction motor is?d",
        "answers": {
            "a": "A",
            "b": "B",
            "c": "C",
            "d": "D"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a three phase induction motor is rotating at steady state. Then if the load is increased then the slip will _____ and the efficiency will",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Decrease ,Increase",
            "b": "Decrease ,Increase",
            "c": "Increase ,Increase",
            "d": "Increase ,Decrease"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a 3-phase IM, maximum torque of 300Nm occur at slip of 10%. The torque at slip of 5% would be____ .",
        "answers": {
            "a": "120Nm",
            "b":"240Nm",
            "c": "150Nm",
            "d": "300Nm"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "For standard 3-phase IM, the rotating direction of motion is-",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Opposite to that of the rotating field",
            "b": "Same as that of the rotating field",
            "c": "Depends in supply voltage phase sequence",
            "d": "Depends in supply voltage phases"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Ns is the synchronous speed and S the slip, then the actual running speed of a three- phase induction motor will be-",
        "answers": {
            "a": "  N~S~",
            "b": "SN~S~",
            "c": "(1-S)N~S~",
            "d": "(N~S~-1)S"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 3-phase 440v, 50Hz induction motor has 4% slip. The frequency of rotor e.m.f. will be-",
        "answers": {
            "a": "200Hz",
            "b": "50Hz",
            "c": "2Hz",
            "d": "0.2Hz"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 6 pole, 50 Hz, 3-phase induction motor is running at 950 rpm. It has rotor copper loss of 5 KW. The rotor input will be -",
        "answers": {
            "a": "100 KW",
            "b": "95 KW",
            "c": "10 KW",
            "d": "5.3 KW"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    }
]